natera.com 2019-11-02

# Natera's Privacy Policy

## Natera Privacy Policy

Updated May 24, 2018

### 1\. General Statement

Natera appreciates your interest in its products and your visit to this website. We take the protection of your data seriously and we want you to feel comfortable visiting our site.

This Privacy Policy applies to Natera Inc. ("us", "we", or "our") which operates the Natera.com website and the subdomains (collectively, “Sites”), and provides access to certain services (“Services”). If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, please do not access or use the Sites, Services or any other aspect of Natera’s business.

This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our Sites and Services and the choices you have associated with that data. We will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information we collect by other means (including offline) or from other sources. The use of information collected through our Sites shall be limited to the purposes under this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use to customers.

### 2\. Information We Collect From You

When you visit our Sites, you may choose to submit information to Natera through our Sites, via e-mail, or by some other means. When you pay a bill using our Sites, you may be asked to enter your name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number and/or credit card information.

If you choose to enroll in our Evercord™ Newborn Stem Cell Banking service (only available to the residents of United States), you may be asked for certain personal information, including but not limited to your name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number, credit card number, and government-issued identification number as well as certain health-related information such as the expected due date, delivery hospital, and doctor or midwife’s name.

We may also ask you for personal information at other times, for example when you answer a survey, when you enter into a sweepstakes, contest or promotion sponsored by us, or when you report a problem with one of our sites or services.

If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence. When you refer a friend or family member for any of our products or services, we may collect the information you provide about that person such as name, mailing address, e-mail address, and/or phone number.

In addition, we may collect information from your computer or Internet device to enable us to offer you the personalized services through our portals and conduct statistical analyses for business purposes. For details, see our Cookie policy provided in Section 5 below.

### 3\. How We Use Your Information

Natera may store and use information collected from you to provide the Services you request, process your online payment made through our Sites, respond and address your submission, for customer service or quality control purposes, or for business effectiveness. The extent to which Natera uses or discloses information depends upon the nature of the information provided and the extent to which Natera’s handling of the information is governed by this privacy policy, our Sites’ terms of use, and applicable law.

If we have obtained explicit consent for marketing, we may use your personal information to provide you with information on our health-related products and services that we think you may find of interest, and to keep you updated on our latest announcements. If we have obtained explicit consent for product development or Research & Development, we may also use personal information for internal purposes to help us develop, deliver and improve our products, services, content, and communications.

From time to time, we may use your personal information to send important notices, such as communications about your account and the services we are providing to you. Because this information is important to your interaction with us, you cannot opt out of receiving these communications.

If you enter into a sweepstakes, contest or similar promotion, we may use the information you provide to administer that program and as otherwise set forth in the sweepstake/contest rules.

With respect to the information collected for Evercord™ New Born Stem Cell Banking Service, we will use the information to process your enrollment and set up your newborn stem cell banking account, and to provide newborn stem cell banking services to you. If you sign up to receive alerts to track your cord blood collection kit, we will use the email address and/or mobile cell phone number you select/provide when signing up to track your kit to provide you with tracking information about your collection kit. If you sign up for our gift registry, we may use and/or display your full name, state and expected due date to personalize your information on our gift registry site and/or in an email that we may send on your behalf announcing your gift registry.

Our Cookie Policy in Section 5 below provides additional details about our use of data and information collected through Cookies.

### 4\. How We Share Your Information

We will keep your information private. We will only share your personal information with third parties as outlined in this policy, and as otherwise required by law.

We may share your personal information with our trusted third parties who assist us in operating and maintaining our websites, analyzing data collected from the websites, processing credit card payments made using our websites, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential.

We may share your personal information when we believe sharing is appropriate and necessary to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. We may also provide non-personally identifiable visitor information to other parties for marketing and advertising purposes. .

We may also share your personal information if all or part of Natera is sold, merged, dissolved, acquired, or involved in a similar transaction.

### 5\. Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies Policy (“Cookie Policy”)

Cookies are small text files that are sent to your computer when you visit a website. We use Cookies to gain useful knowledge about how our Sites are used so that we can keep improving them for users like you. For example, Cookies on Natera’s Sites let you navigate between pages efficiently, store your preferences and generally improve your experience of our Sites. When you visit our Sites, you will have the opportunity to review this Privacy Policy including our Cookie Policy. You will be asked to accept or decline our policies. We will record your IP address, time and date and your choice. If you limit the ability of our Sites to set Cookies, you may experience a less than optimal and/or lose the ability to access the services, since it will no longer be personalized to you. It may also stop you from saving customized settings, like login information.

We may use structural or navigational cookies so that we can render the web pages efficiently including your preferences. The structural or navigational cookies will be initiated prior to you accepting our cookie policies. If you accept our policies, we will use Cookies tracking cookies and other tracking technologies for the following purposes:

(a). If you use our patient portal that will require registration to access content for most sections of the portal, we will place an “authentication cookie” on your computer. This may allow you to leave and return to these parts of the Site without re-authenticating yourself.

(b). Natera likes to understand how visitors use our websites by using web analytics services. They count the number of visitors and tell us things about the visitors’ behavior overall – such as identifying the search engine keywords that lead the user to the site, the typical length of stay on the site or the average number of pages a particular user views. We may also use services such as Google Analytics to track web statistics. In this case, Google will place a “3rd party cookie” on your computer.

(c). Additionally, your browser or mobile application will automatically report your log file information each time you access our Site automatically reports your log file information. We may use this information to analyze the site usage for business purposes.

### 6\. Data Processing and Transfers

When you use or interact with any Services offered through our Sites, you consent to the data processing, sharing, transferring and uses of your information as outlined in this Privacy Policy. Regardless of the country where you reside, you authorize us to transfer, process, store and use your information in countries other than your own in accordance with this Privacy Policy and to provide you with Services. Some of these countries may not have the same legal data protection safeguards as the country where you reside.

We may process information related to individuals in the EU and may transfer that information from the EU by using various compliance mechanisms, including informed consent and/or data processing agreements based on EU approved language. By using our Sites and Services, you consent to us transferring information about you as needed.

### 7\. How We Protect Your Information

Natera takes appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure, or destruction of data by maintaining it on servers with restricted access and other security precautions. As confirmed by the secure website certificate, any information that you provide to or receive from our websites is encrypted, and therefore protected against interception by others, using Secure Sockets Layer (“SSL”) encryption technology. After you complete a financial transaction through our websites, your private information (credit cards, financials, etc.) will not be stored. Despite these efforts, we cannot guarantee that our security measures will be able to completely defeat all unauthorized accesses attempts.

To learn more about current practices and policies regarding security and confidentiality of the Services, please contact us at [info@natera.com](mailto:info@natera.com.?subject=Contact%20the%20DPO)

### 8\. Compromise of Personal Information

In the event that we discover that the safety of your personal information is compromised, Natera will promptly attempt to notify you in compliance with applicable law.

### 9\. Data Access, Correction, Deletion, and Opting Out

(a). _Your right to Inspect and Receive a Copy of Your Personal Information:_ You may ask to review for accuracy or to receive a copy of your personal information that is included in our records. You may request this by sending your request using the URL [www.natera.com/contact-us/PI](https://pages.natera.com/contact-the-dpo). The data will be provided to you in a CSV format.

(b). _Updating your Personal Information:_ You have the right to ask us to correct your information in our records if you believe it is inaccurate. If we determine that your information is inaccurate, we will correct it as permitted by law, and after we verify your identity. If a different health care facility or professional created the information that you want to change, you should ask them to amend the information.  
Natera customers who have a patient portal account, can review, correct, update or delete inaccuracies to the information about you by logging into your account. You may also request this by sending your request using the URL [www.natera.com/contact-us/PI](https://pages.natera.com/contact-the-dpo).

(c). _Right to Erasing Your Information:_ You have the right to request us to delete your personal information collected by us, unless it is required by law to be retained. You can do so by submitting a request to us at the URL [www.natera.com/contact-us/PI](https://pages.natera.com/contact-the-dpo). We will confirm doing so when complete.

(d). _Updating Consent:_ You may wish to withdraw an authorization you gave us before (Opt-out). Opting out should be submitted to us via the URL <https://pages.natera.com/contact-the-dpo>. The withdrawal of consent will apply to future use and disclosures of your personal information unless required by law. It will not affect previous processing, while your authorization was in effect. We will also share your updated preferences to the third parties.

We may retain needed information for as long as your account is active with us or as needed to provide you services. We may retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

### 10\. Children’s Privacy

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. For that reason, Natera does not knowingly collect or accept personal information from anyone under the age of 16. Children under the age of 16 may not use our websites. Moreover, anyone under 18 years old should seek their parent or guardian's permission prior to using or disclosing any personal data through our Sites.

### 11\. Notification Procedures

It is our policy to provide notifications, whether such notifications are required by law or are for marketing or other business-related purposes, to you via email, written or hard copy notice, or through conspicuous posting of such notice on the Service, as determined by Natera in its sole discretion. For legally required notifications and service notifications, we reserve the right to determine the form and means of providing notifications to you. You might not be able to opt out of some notifications. For marketing related notifications, we reserve the right to determine the form and means of communication to you, unless you have opted out of receiving marketing messages from Natera.

### 12\. Links to and from Other Web Sites

We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites or services linked to or from the Natera’s Sites, including the information or content contained therein. Please remember that when you use a link to go from our Sites/Portals to another website or service, our Privacy Policy does not apply to third-party websites or services. Your browsing and interaction on any third-party website or service, including those that have links on our website, are subject to that third party’s own rules and policies. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of third party websites or services before providing any of them with your personal information.

### 13\. Social Media Widgets

Our Sites include social media features, such as the Facebook Like button, Twitter button and other widgets. If we have obtained consent, these features may collect your IP address and the address of pages you are visiting on our Site, and may set cookies to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets may be hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Sites. Your interactions with features hosted on 3rd party sites are governed by the privacy policy of the organization providing it.

### 14\. Changes to Our Privacy Policy

All changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page. When we change the policy in a material manner, we will let you know via email and/or a prominent notice on our Site, prior to the change becoming effective and we will update the ‘effective date’ at the top of this page.

### 15\. Actions You May Take

If you have questions or wish to exercise your privacy rights, believe that we may have violated these rights, or disagree with a decision that we made about access to your information, you may contact us at the following address or telephone number:

**Our Address and Contact Information is:**

If you are from US or other countries excluding EU countries, our Representative is:

Privacy Officer  
Natera, Inc.  
201 Industrial Road, Suite 410  
San Carlos, CA 94070  
United States of America  
Tel: (650) 249-9090

If you are from the EU, our Representative is:

Data Protection Officer (DPO)  
Natera, Inc.  
201 Industrial Road, Suite 410  
San Carlos, CA 94070  
United States of America  
Tel: +1 (650) 249-9090
